chapter 3.
It took me a long time to learn where he
came from.
The little prince, who asked me so many
questions, never seemed to hear the ones
I asked him.
It was the words dropped by chance that,
little by little, everything was revealed
to me.
The first time he saw my airplane, for
instance (I shall not draw my airplane;
that would be much too complicated for
me),
he asked me:
"What is that object?"
"That is not an object. It flies. It is an
airplane.
It is my airplane."
And I was proud to have him know that I
could fly.
He cried out, then:
"What
drop down from the sky?"
"Yes,"
I replied modestly.
"Oh
it is funny!"
And a little prince broke into a lovely
peel of laughter,
which irritated me very much.
I like my misfortunes to be taken
seriously.
Then he added:
"So you two come from the sky!
Which is your planet?"
At that moment I caught a gleam of light
in the impenetrable mystery of his
presence; and at once questioned him
Do you come from another planet?"
But he did not reply.
He tossed his head gently, without taking
his eyes from my airplane
It is true that on that you can't have
come from very far away..."
And he sunk into a long reverie
Then, taking my sheep out of his pocket,
he buried himself in the contemplation
of his treasure.
You can imagine how my curiosity was
aroused by this half-confidence about
the "other planets."
I made a great effort, therefore, to find
out a little more on this subject.
"My little man,
where do you come from?
What is this 'where I live,' of which you
speak?
Where do you want to take your sheep?"
After a reflective silence he replied
what I really like about the box you
have given me is that he can use it as
his house during the night
That is so.
And if you're good I will also give you
a string to time up during the day, and
opposed to time to."
But the little prince seems shocked by
my offer of the string
Tie him up What a queer idea!"
"But if you don't time up he will wander
off somewhere, and get lost."
My friend then broke into another appeal
of laughter again
where do you think he would go?"
"Anywhere.
Straight ahead of him
the little prince then said Gravely
That doesn't matter
everything is so small where I live
And perhaps with a little hint of
sadness, he added:
"Straight ahead of him
he cannot go very far